Guide to the Margaret Morse Nice papers, 1917-1968
Nice, Margaret Morse papers, 1917-1968
- Series II. Professional papers
  - Scholarly manuscripts
    - 5 undated papers (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - 2 papers, 1931 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Broadcast, 1933 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Broadcast, 1933 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Lectures, 1933 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - 2 articles, 1934 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Role of territory in bird life, abstract, article to p. 20 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Territory, pp. 21-50, 1939 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Paper: Carolina Wren, undated ( 1946 ?) (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Desert and mountain in South Arizona, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - AOU abstracts, Incubation Periods throughout the Ages, 1951-1952 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Injury feigning, articles, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - 1956 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - misc. lectures given by ornithological authors (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Schantz, photos (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Bibliography of Territory, 1933 (1) (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Bibliography of Territory, 1933 (2) (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Bibliography of Territory, 1933 (3) (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Aristotle & Territory, the earliest mention ( 1933 ) (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Schantz, photos, robin's nest, warblers (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Cowbird (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Drawings (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Drawings (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Aristotle (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Sources, awakening songs for article, Apr. 1938 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Ducklings (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Ducks, incubation periods (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - ornithological articles, Evans ( 1891 ) to present ( 1957 ) (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Articles, enemy recognition, outline for articles, Joost, charts (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Gnatcatcher (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Handbooks (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Handbook notes (nesting notes) (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Incubation periods of ovipaous animals (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Martins, miscellaneous notes (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Martins, notes (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Nesting success records (1) (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Nesting success records (2) (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Owls, miscellaneous notes (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Raven, notes (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Raven, miscellaneous notes (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - References (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Robins, miscellaneous notes (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Respiration data (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Swallows (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Red-eyed Vireos (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Weather data, 1929-1931 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Weight records (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Weight records (1) (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Weight records (2) (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Weight records (3) (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - White Throat, weight records (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Photographs from publications (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - White Throat, miscellaneous notes and maps (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Auklets (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Biographical material, "A Partial Bibliography of Margaret Morse Nice" (2 copies) (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Notebooks
      - Series of Song Sparrow notes (Box 17)
        - 1 series--30 vols.
        - 1 series--8 vols.
      - Series of bird sighting notebooks (Box 17)
      - Series of Ohio Olentangy Birds (5 vols.) (Box 17)
      - Red-eyed Vireo (Box 17)
      - Robin (Box 17)
      - Ohio Doves (Box 17)
      - Myrtle Warbler (Box 17)
      - Carolina Wren (Box 17)
      - Ovenbirds (2 vols.) (Box 17)
      - Least Flycatcher (Box 17)
      - Interpont data (Box 17)
      - Black Throated Green Warbler (Box 17)
      - Summer Birds of Pelham, Mass. (Box 17)
      - Arkansas (Box 17)
      - Miscellaneous others (Box 17)
      - Bird Census, 1952 (Box 18)
      - Ohio 1, Columbus, Ohio, Jan. 1928-June 1929 (Box 18)
      - Ohio 2, Columbus, Ohio, Sept. 1929-Aug. 1930 (Box 18)
      - Ohio 3, Sept. 1930-Oct. 1931 (Box 18)
      - Ohio 4, Nov. 1911-Dec. 1932 (Box 18)
      - Ohio 6, Bird Census, Jan. 1934-Apr. 1935 (Box 18)
      - Ovenbirds III, 1927 (Box 18)
- Series III. Reprints
  - Reprints on ornithological topics, by Margaret Morse Nice, 1938-1946 (Box 20)